Finding Aid for the Carol Burnett Papers PASC.0066
UCLA Library Special Collections
Carol Burnett papers
1961-1994
UCLA Library Special Collections
Burnett, Carol
Burnett, Carol--Archives.
PASC.0066
32.0 linear feet (64 boxes)
1.25 linear feet (1 unprocessed flat box)
The Carol Burnett papers contains press clippings, photographs, scripts, musical arrangements, personal and business correspondence, sound recorded albums, artwork, awards and scrapbooks.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carol Burnett, 1985.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942304293606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography/History
Carol Burnett was born in San Antonio, Texas in 1933 and moved to Los Angeles when she was a child. She attended UCLA as an undergraduate (1951-1954), first as a journalism major before discovering the musical theater department where she excelled. During the 1950s, Burnett was a frequent guest on television variety programs such as The Dinah Shore Show, The Ed Sullivan Show and The Jack Paar Tonight Show. She became a regular cast member on The Gary Moore Show (1959-1962) where she won her first Emmy. Burnett appeared in several television specials in the 1960s such as Calamity Jane (1963), Carol and Company (1963, 1966) and Julie [Andrews] and Carol at Carnegie Hall (1963), before launching her own weekly variety program The Carol Burnett Show (1966-1978). Her other television projects include Friendly Fire (1979), The Tenth Month (1979) and guest appearances on programs such as All My Children (1983-1995), Mad About You (1986-1999) and Law and Order: Special Victims Unit (2009).
Known for her work in television, Burnett has also appeared in stage and film productions. She made her Broadway debut in the musical Once Upon a Mattress (1959) and has starred in numerous stage performances such as Fade Out, Fade In (1964), I Do! I Do! (1973), Same Time, Next Year (1977, 1980) and Moon Over Buffalo (1995). Her film projects include Pete 'n' Tillie (1972), A Wedding (1978), The Four Seasons (1980) and Annie (1982).
Carol Burnett has been honored throughout her career. She is the recipient of several awards and tributes including a Peabody Award (1963), numerous Emmy, Golden Globe and People's Choice awards and was inducted into the Television Hall of Fame in 1985.
Scope and Content
Arranged in the following series: Series 1. Motion Picture Projects; Series 2. Stage and Live Performance Projects; Series 3. Television Projects; Series 4. Artwork; Series 5. Awards and Certificates; Series 6. Photographs; Series 7. Press Clippings; Series 8. Scrapbooks.
This collection consists of press clippings, photographs, scripts, musical arrangements, personal and business correspondence, sound recorded albums, artwork, awards and scrapbooks.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Motion Picture Projects, 1963-1982. 5 manuscript boxes; 1 flat box
Series 2. Stage and Live Performance Projects, 1952-1999. 17 manuscript boxes; 3 flat boxes
Series 3. Television Projects, 1956-2005. 34 manuscript boxes; 56 flat boxes
Series 4. Artwork (box 6), 1964-2003. 2 flat boxes
Series 5. Awards and Certificates, 1963-2002. 1 manuscript box; 3 legal boxes; 1 flat box
Series 6. Photographs, 1940s-2003. 9 manuscript boxes; 3 flat boxes
Series 7. Press Clippings, 1955-2000s. 11 manuscript boxes
Series 8. Scrapbooks, 1956-1991. 1 manuscript box; 8 flat boxes
Series 9. The Carol Burnett Show (Music). unknown
Series 10. Sound Recordings, 1967-1972. 1 legal box
Series 11. Correspondence/Biographic Material, 1947-1978. 9 manuscript boxes
Series 12. Writings, 1975-2003. 1 manuscript box; 1 flat box
Series 13. Music, 1958, 1965, undated. 1 flat box
Related Material
Carol Burnett Collection (Collection PASC 165). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Arnold Rosen Collection of Carol Burnett Show Script Materials (Collection PASC 67). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Nat Farber Collection of Television Show Music Arrangements (Collection PASC 33-M). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Carol Burnett memorabilia collection (Collection PASC 224-M). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Actresses -- United States -- Archives.; Burnett, Carol
- Motion Picture Projects, 1963-1982; Series 1.; 5 manuscript boxes; 1 flat box
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains materials related to motion picture projects featuring Carol Burnett such as the feature films "Annie," "The Four Seasons," "Health," "Pete 'n' Tillie" and "A Wedding." Materials included in this series are photographs, scrapbooks, press clippings and film posters.
  Arrangement note
  The sub-series are arranged in alphabetical order according to record title.
  - Annie, 1982; Subseries 1.; 1 boxes
    Contents are arranged in alphabetical order according to record title.
    This sub-series includes materials related to the feature film "Annie," co-starring Carol Burnett, Albert Finney, Ann Reinking, Tim Curry and Bernadette Peters. The film was directed by John Houston for Colombia Pictures. Materials include production stills, cast photos and three scrapbooks containing press clippings and press releases.
    - Press clippings, 1982; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Press clippings for the film Annie.
    - Production program, 1982; Paper program (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Paper program released by studio--Rastar and Columbia Pictures-- for the film; includes cast credits and production notes.
    - Production stills, 1982; 12 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Production stills from the film Annie. Photographs include: Carol Burnett, Aileen Quinn, Bernadette Peters, Tim Curry, Ann Reinking, Geoffrey Holder, Albert Finney.
    - Production stills, 1982; 5 photos; 8"x10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Production stills of Carol Burnett in Annie. Includes some duplicates.
    - Production stills, 1982; 7 photographs; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Production stills from the film Annie. Includes: Carol Burnett, Aileen Quinn, Bernadette Peters, Tim Curry, Ann Reinking, Geoffrey Holder, Albert Finney.
    - Production stills, 1982; 7 photographs, 8" x 10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Four Seasons (The), 1982; Subseries 2.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series includes materials related to the feature film "The Four Seasons," co-starring Carol Burnett, Alan Alda, Sandy Dennis, Rita Moreno and Jack Weston; written and directed by Alan Alda for Universal Studios. Materials include a book of photographs by Arlene Alda (Alan Alda's wife,) documenting the making of the film; New York: Simon and Schuster, 1981.
    - Four Season (The), 1980; Paperback book (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Book of photographs, by Arlene Alda (Alan Alda's wife), documenting the making of the film; New York: Simon and Schuster, 1981.
    - Production still, 1981; 1 photograph; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Production still of cast from the film Four Seasons. Includes Carol Burnett, Alan Alda, Rita Moreno, Jack Weston, Bess Armstrong, Len Cariou.
  - Health, 1980; Subseries 3.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains a scrapbook with photographs related to the feature film "Health," co-starring Carol Burnett, Glenda Jackson, James Garner, Lauren Bacall and Paul Dooley; directed by Robert Altman for 20th Century Fox.
    - Health, 1980; Brown leather album (Box 5)
      This scrapbook contains photographs of the cast and crew during the making of feature film Health, starring Carol Burnett with Glenda Jackson, James Garner, Lauren Bacall and Paul Dooley; dir. Robert Altman; 20th Century Fox.
    - Production notes, 1980; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Production notes on the film Health; includes cast and crew bios.
  - Pete 'n' Tillie, 1972; Subseries 4.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains materials related to the feature film "Pete 'n' Tillie," co-starring Carol Burnett and Walter Matthau; directed by Marting Ritt for Universal Pictures.
    - Photographs, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Productions stills of Carol Burnett, Walter Matthau, Geraldine Page in the film Pete 'n' Tillie.
    - Press clippings, 1973; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Press clippings from the film Pete 'n' Tillie.
  - Wedding (A), 1978; Subseries 5.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains materials, including a scrapbook of photos, pertaining to the feature film "The Wedding," co-starring Carol Burnett, Paul Dooley, Mia Farrow, Desi Arnaz Jr. and Geraldine Chaplin; directed by Robert Altman for 20th Century Fox.
    - Production notebook, No date [1978]; Notebook (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Production/publicity notebook with information pertaining to the film's characters.
    - Production still, 1978; 1 photograph; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Production still of Carol Burnett and Pat McCormick from the film A Wedding.
    - Scrapbook, 1978; White album (Box 5)
      Scrapbook of photographs of cast and crew during the making of A Wedding.
  - Who's Been Sleeping in My Bed, 1963; Subseries 6.
    This sub-series includes material related to the feature film "Who's Been Sleeping in My Bed," co-starring Carol Burnett, Dean Martin and Elizabeth Montgomery; directed by Daniel Mann and written by Jack Rose for Paramount Pictures. Material includes multiple film posters.
    - Who's Been Sleeping in My Bed, 1963; 4 movie posters; 3, 11"x14"; 1, 25"x28" (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Three smaller movie posters each containing different images from the film; one larger film poster. All materials are in color.
- Stage and Live Performance Projects, 1952-1999; Series 2.; 17 manuscript boxes; 3 flat boxes
  The Stage and Live Performance Projects series consists of materials related to live performances and/or appearances featuring Carol Burnett. Materials include correspondence, photographs, press clippings, scrapbooks, show programs and sound recordings. Projects include "The Carol Burnett Show," "Fade Out, Fade In," "Once Upon a Mattress," "I Do! I Do!" and performances given at the White House in 1962, 1965, 1969, and 1975.
  - Company (The), 1993; Subseries 1.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains press clippings, theater programs and photographs from the stage performance of "The Company," starring Carol Burnett; presented by Long Beach Civic Light Opera, Long Beach, California.
    - Company (The), 1993; Folder (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Contains theater programs; press clippings; photographs. 11 4"x7" color snap shots of the performance taken by Elena M. Breckenridge, Make-up Artist; 1 8"x10" b/w of cast and crew.
  - Fade Out, Fade In, 1964; Subseries 2.; 4 boxes
    This sub-series contains materials related to the Broadway musical "Fade Out, Fade In," (originally titled "Girl to Remember") starring Carol Burnett, Jack Cassidy, Lou Jacobi and Tiger Haynes; directed by George Abbott; music by Jule Styne; book and lyrics by Betty Comden and Adolph Green. Materials include: show program, press clippings and two copies of the sound recorded album featuring the original Broadway cast.
    - A Girl to Remember, Lila Tremain, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Arrangement (music and lyrics).
    - Congratulations telegrams, September 25, 1964; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Telegrams addressed to Joe Hamilton and Carol Burnett congratulating them on the opening of Fade Out, Fade In.
      General note
      Telegrams were originally located in a folder in scrapbook (Box 31).
    - Correspondence-production paperwork, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Contains materials pertaining to Fade Out, Fade In: document of Carol Burnett Disciplinary Proceeding for Actors' Equity Association; note to Burnett from Betty Comden and Adolph Green; 4 letters to Burnett from co-star Tiger Haynes; Fade Out, Fade In company sign-in list; letter from Jule Styne to Burnett regarding script pages of the "first scene"; script pages for Scene I (2 pages).
    - Legal contract, Girl to Remember, January 1963; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Legal contract for Carol Burnett regarding the play Girl to Remember later retitled Fade Out, Fade In.
    - Photographs, 1964; 12 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Production stills of Fade Out, Fade In; and a dinner celebration that includes Carol Burnett, co-star Tiger Haynes and several unidentified individuals; one photo of Shubert Theater marquee; one photo of Burnett and cast members with signs welcoming her back. Contains 10 photographs, 8" X 10".
    - Poster, 1964; Poster; 22" x 14", color (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Theater poster for performance of Fade Out, Fade In.
    - Press clipping envelope, 1964; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Contains original envelop (with addresses) for press clippings sent from McFadden, Strauss, Eddy, Irwin & Goodman Public Relations to Joe Hamilton.
    - Press clippings; book agreement, 1963; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 24)
      Loose press clippings; legal document from the law offices of Squadron, Alter & Weinrib for Carol Burnett to sign approving the book of the play "Girl to Remember" (retitled "Fade Out, Fade In").
    - Production and cast stills, 1964; Photographs; 20, 8"x10", b/w (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Production and cast rehearsal stills of Fade Out, Fade In. Photos include Carol Burnett, Tiger Haynes, Dick Patterson, Tina Louise.
      Photographs originally located inside a folder in scrapbook (Box 31).
    - Show programs, 1965; 4 programs (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Show programs from original Broadway musical production of Fade Out, Fade In.
    - Sound recordings, 1964; Sound recordings; 2 albums (Box 23)
      Two sound recorded albums of the Broadway musical featuring the original cast: Carol Burnett, Jack Cassidy, Lou Jacobi.
  - From the Top!, 1993; Subseries 3.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains material from the stage musical "From the Top!" three "mini musicals" containing bits from songs written by Irving Berlin, Cole Porter and Ira Gershwin; starring Carol Burnett; written by Ken and Mitzie Welch; musical director Don Chrichton; directed by Glenn Casale; presented by the Long Beach Civic Light Opera, Long Beach, California. Materials include: press clippings, show programs, cast/crew photographs, production stills.
    - Photographs, 1993; 19 photographs & slides (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Contains b/w cast and crew production stills and two color slides. Photographs taken by Spike Nannarello. Includes 17 photographs, 8"x10", b/w.
    - Photographs, 1993; 2 envelops of photographs; various sizes, color (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Backstage/dressing room color photographs of key cast members. Includes photographs: 24, 5"X3 1/2"; 31, 4"x6"; 36, 5"X7".
    - Press clippings, 1993; Loose clippings (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Contains loose press clippings.
    - Press clippings & show programs, 1993; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Contains press clippings and orginal show programs.
  - Greek Theater (The), 1966; Subseries 4.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series includes material related to a live performance at The Greek Theater, Los Angeles, California, August 8-14, 1966, featuring Carol Burnett, Jackie Vernon and The Good Time Singers; musical director Harry Zimmerman; produced by Joe Hamilton. Materials include: production stills, backstage photos with Burnett, Joe Hamilton, Julie Andrews and Jackie Vernon, press clippings, show programs and personal telegrams addressed to Burnett.
    - Photographs, 1966; 15 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Contains photographs of Carol Burnett on stage alone and backstage with Julie Andrews, Joe Hamilton, Jackie Vernon. Photographs taken by Doris Nieh and Wilson Millar.
    - Press materials & telegrams, 1966; Folder (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Contains press clippings; show program; personal telegrams to Carol Burnett from people such as Rock Hudson, David Berman, Bob Wright.
  - I Do! I Do!, 1973; Subseries 5.; 1 boxes
    Contents are rranged in alphabetical order according to record title.
    This sub-series contains material related to the stage production of "I Do! I Do!" starring Carol Burnett and Rock Hudson.
    - Annotated script, May 16, 1974; Script (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Annotated script for stage production of I Do! I Do! starring Carol Burnett and Rock Hudson.
    - Scrapbook, 1973; 1 folder, loose pages (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Loose pages of scrapbook of performance I Do! I Do! starring Carol Burnett and Rock Hudson; pages in original order. Contains theater program, production stills and press clippings. Original book cover had label that said: "I Do! I Do!"
      In original order; pages separated by a sheet of acid free paper.
    - Theater programs, 1973; 2 programs (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Two different programs for the performance of I Do! I Do! starring Carol Burnett and Rock Hudson.
  - Julie and Carol at Carnegie Hall, 1963; Subseries 6.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series includes materials related to Julie Andrews and Carol Burnett's live performance at Carnegie Hall that was also broadcast on television. Andrews and Burnett also performed together at Lincoln Center (1971) and reunited for the 1992 television special "AT T Presents Julie and Carol: Together Again." Both the Carnegie Hall live performance and "Julie and Carol: Together Again" are also found in Series 3: Television Projects.
    - Photographs, 1963; 8 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Contains photographs of Julie Andrews and Carol Burnett together off stage and production stills of them performing; Andrews alone; Andrews, Burnett and Eve Arden; contact sheet of photos with Andrews and Burnett, Andrews, Burnett and Arden and Andrews and first husband, Tony Walton; Andrews and Walton with daughter Emma Walton.
      Photograph of Andrews, Walton and daughter Emma Walton originally located in folder with "Julie and Carol at President's Ball 1965" written on it in a scrapbook (Box 31).
    - Printed sheet music, 1963; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Contains printed sheet music of song "Meantime" from the television production Julie and Carol at Carnegie Hall; lyrics Al Stillman, music Robert Allen; Columbia Records.
  - Julie and Carol at Lincoln Center, 1971; Subseries 7.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series includes materials related to Julie Andrews and Carol Burnett's live performance at Lincoln Center that was also broadcast on television. Materials include: sound recorded album and published music. Andrews and Burnett also performed together at Carnegie Hall (1963) and reunited for the television special "AT T Presents Julie and Carol: Together Again" (1992.) Both the Carnegie Hall live performance and "Julie and Carol: Together Again" can also be found in Series 3: Television Projects.
    - Photographs, 1971; 3 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Contains production stills of Carol Burnett and Julie Andrews performing as part of the television special Julie and Carol at Lincoln Center; second photo of Burnett and Andrews during rehearsal. Photographs include 2, 7"x9", b/w; 1, 8"x10", b/w.
    - Press Clippings, 1971; Loose press clippings (Box 18, Folder 10)
      Assorted press clippings for Julie and Carol at Lincoln Center.
      Researchers should cross reference Clipping series files for 1971.
    - Sound recording, 1971; 1 sound recording (Box 23)
      Contains sound recorded album of live performance by Julie Andrews and Carol Burnett at Lincoln Center. Songs include: Medley of the 60s--Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band, The Beat Goes On, Leaving on a Jet Plane, Sesame Street.
    - Sound recording, 1972; 1 12" sound disc (Box 23)
      Publisher no.: S 31153
      Sound recording of Julie and Carol at Lincoln Center.
  - Love Letters, 1990, 1993; Subseries 8.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series includes materials pertaining to the stage performance of "Love Letters," produced in 1990 and starring Carol Burnett and Charlton Heston and in 1993 starring Burnett and Cliff Robertson. Materials include: show programs; photographs slides.
    - Production stills & slides, 1990; 3 slides; 35 mm, color; 4 photographs, various sizes, color (Box 60, Folder 18)
      Contains production stills and slides of Carol Burnett and Charlton Heston.
    - Show program, 1993; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Contains show program for 1993 production co-starring Cliff Robertson; dir. Robert Sallin; Sun Valley Repertory Company, Idaho.
  - Moon Over Buffalo, 1995; Subseries 9.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains material related to the Broadway production of "Moon Over Broadway," starring Carol Burnett and Philip Bosco. Materials include: press clippings and production photographs.
    - Moon Over Buffalo, 1995; Loose clippings (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Contains loose press clippings for Broadway performance of Moon Over Buffalo.
    - Moon Over Buffalo, 1995 October (Box 39)
      Martin Beck Theatre (NYC) production.
    - Photographs, 1995; 10 photographs; 8"x10", b/w & color (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Contains 7 color xerox and 3 b/w production stills from Broadway performance of Moon Over Buffalo.
    - Poster, 1995; Poster, 22" x 14", color (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Theater poster for production of Moon Over Buffalo.
  - Once Upon a Mattress, 1959; Subseries 10.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains material related to the original Broadway musical starring Carol Burnett (a role originated by Burnett). Materials include scripts, photographs and recorded albums. "Once Upon a Mattress" was produced and broadcast for television three times--1964, 1972, and 2005. In 1999, Burnett was a Regents' Professor and directed the UCLA Music Department's student production of the musical. Researchers should cross references the title "Once Upon a Mattress" with the other sub-series by the same name and different year, in Series 3: Television Projects and Series 2: Stage and Live Performance.
    - Photographs, 1959-1960; 2 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Contains 2 photographs of window display advertisement with life size figure of Carol Burnett for Once Upon a Mattress.
    - Poster, 1959; Poster; 22" x 14", color (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Contains theater poster for performance of Once Upon a Mattress.
    - Show program, letters of congratulations, 1959; Show program; 4 copies (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Contains show programs for the original Broadway musical performed in 1959 starring Carol Burnett, Joe Bova, Jack Gilford, Jane White, Harry Snow; magazine Theatre Arts (July 1960) contains complete script of play; cards and telegrams congratulating Burnett on finishing the show.
    - Sound recording, 1959; Sound recording; 2 albums (Box 23)
      Contains 2 sound recorded albums of the musical featuring the original cast: Carol Burnett, Joe Bova, Jack Gilford, Jane White, Harry Snow.
  - Once Upon a Mattress, 1999; Subseries 11.; 1 boxes